Ayham Shokier

Ankawa Erbil, Iraq

Email: ayhamsho777@live.com Mobile: +964 751 849 7984

Professional Summary

Reliable Administration Manage, Public Relations Coordinator, Supervisor, Sales and Cashier with Bachelor Degree, and background in Customer Services Accounting, team work and fast learning with 13 years of experience.

Personal Information

Birth Date: 23 October 1983

Gender: Male **Nationality:** Syrian **Marital Status:** Married

Driving License: United Arab Emirates - Valid

Academic Qualifications

ISO 31000 Risk management stander 2017

G31000 Institute - Dubai - UAE

• Leadership for Administrative Professionals 2017

Eton Institute – Dubai –UAE

• English for Business Skills 2017

Bayt.com - Dubai - UAE

• Customer Service Professionals 2013

Azadea Group - Dubai -UAE

Customer Focus Skills 2012

Azadea Group - Dubai -UAE

Bachelor Degree of Accounting 2010

Damascus University- Syria

English Courses 2006

Business vocabulary in use - Syria

Course in Stock- Exchange 2005

Forex trading - Syria

Languages

Arabic: Mother tong

• English: Excellent

Skills

- Customer and Personal Service
- Friendly
- **Building Trust**
- Flexible schedule
- Quick-thinking
- Teamwork
- **English Language**
- **Punctuality**
- Administration and Management
- Speaking
- Coordination
- Time Management
- Personnel and Human Resources
- Negotiation
- Social Perceptiveness
- Monitoring
- **Complex Problem Solving**
- **Active Learning**
- Sales and Marketing
- **Public Speaking & Presentations**

Experience

Administration Manager

Right Bright Cleaning Services Dubai, **United Arab Emirates**

- Accomplishes staff results by communicating job expectations; planning, monitoring, and appraising job results; coaching, counseling, and disciplining employees; initiating, coordinating, and enforcing systems, policies, and procedures.
- Provides supplies by identifying needs of equipment's and materials, establishing policies, procedures, and work schedules.
- Provides communication systems by identifying needs; evaluating options; maintaining equipment; approving invoices.
- Completes special projects by organizing and coordinating information and requirements; planning, arranging, and meeting schedules; monitoring results.
- Achieves financial objectives by anticipating requirements; submitting information for budget preparation; scheduling expenditures; monitoring costs; analyzing variances.
- Maintains professional and technical knowledge by attending educational workshops; benchmarking professional standards; reviewing professional publications; establishing personal networks

Public Relations Coordinator (PRO)

02/2015 to 10/2015

Right Bright Cleaning Services Dubai, **United Arab Emirates**

- Submit and ensure the processing of all types of applications and paperwork to the local government bodies, including but not limited to visit visas, employment or residence visas, car registrations, Trade License, labor permits, export license, economic license, foreign license, etc.
- Proactively manage the timely renewal of all Employment Visas and Labor Permits, and company related licenses.
- Assist employees in the process of renewing visas for their immediate dependents.

11/2015 to 07/2018

- Manage the visa checklist as when the rules on visa/labor changes.
- Assist the company and the employees with visa arrangements in Embassies.
- Maintain database of all passports and residence visas by scanning all documents and directly updating the database when details change.
- Accurately prepare and process required legal documents like rent contract attestation in government agencies such as Ministry of Economic, Court, Chamber of Commerce, Traffic Department and Municipality.
- Makes sure all business and trade Licenses are updated, follow-up official approvals and permits, to prevent unnecessary violation

Property Consultant

02/2014 to 01/2015

FMF Real Estate Broker Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Rent or lease properties.
- Purchase offers to sellers for consideration
- Generate lists of properties that are compatible with buyers' needs and financial resources.
- Interview clients to determine what kinds of properties they are seeking.
- Prepare documents such as representation contracts, purchase agreements, closing statements, deeds and leases.
- Coordinate property closings, overseeing signing of documents and disbursement of funds.
- Act as an intermediary in negotiations between buyers and sellers, generally representing one or the other.
- Promote sales of properties through advertisements, open houses, and participation in multiple listing services.
- Display residential properties to clients and explain their features.
- Answer clients' questions regarding construction work, financing, maintenance, repairs, and appraisals.
- Inspect condition of premises, and arrange for necessary maintenance or notify owners of maintenance needs.
- Accompany buyers during visits to and inspections of property, advising them on the suitability and value of the homes they are visiting.
- Advise sellers on how to make homes more appealing to potential buyers.
- Arrange meetings between buyers and sellers when details of transactions need to be negotiated.
- Advise clients on market conditions, prices, mortgages, legal requirements and related matters.
- Contact property owners and advertise services in order to solicit property sales listings.
- Visit properties to assess them before showing them to clients.
- Contact utility companies for service hookups to clients' property.
- Solicit and compile listings of available rental properties.
- Rent or lease properties on behalf of clients.

Supervisor / Cashier Azadea Group /ZARA Dubai, United Arab Emirates

01/2009 to 01/2014

- Supervises, coordinates, directs, and monitors staff activities to ensure prompt,
 Courteous and accurate responses are provided to customers.
- Assisting the team by performing the tasks with them Helping with training and development -Reporting to senior management / personnel when required Ensures adherence to departmental andservice center policies, procedures, and Practices.
- Recommends and implements new or improved systems to enhance or expedite work.
- Creates and maintains a positive, respectful work environment for staff.

- Develops job aids to clarify/simplify processing procedures Handling complaints (from both staff and customers) Ensure that each customer receives outstanding service by providing a friendly environment, which includes greeting and acknowledging every customer, maintaining solid product knowledge and all other aspects of customer service.
- Assist in processing and replenishing merchandise.
- Aid customers in locating merchandise.
- Communicate customer requests to management.
- Participate in year-end inventory and cycle counts.
- Assist in ringing up sales at registers and/or bagging merchandise.

Sales /property consultant

03/2008 to 01/2009

Emirates Prodeal Real Estate Dubai, United Arab Emirates

- Rent or lease properties purchase offers to sellers for consideration Generate lists of properties are compatible with buyers' that needs and financial resources.
- Interview clients to determine what kinds of properties they are seeking.
- Prepare documents such as representation contracts, purchase agreements, closing statements, deeds and leases Coordinate property closings, overseeing signing of documents and disbursement of funds.
- Act as an intermediary in negotiations between buyers and sellers, generally representing one or the other.
- Promote sales of properties through advertisements, open houses, and participation in multiple listing services.
- Display residential properties to clients and explain their features.
- Answer clients' questions regarding construction work, financing, maintenance, repairs, and appraisals.
- Inspect condition of premises, and arrange for necessary maintenance or notify owners of maintenance needs.
- Accompany buyers during visits to and inspections of property, advising them on the suitability and value of the homes they are visiting.
- Advise sellers on how to make homes more appealing to potential buyers.
- Arrange meetings between buyers and sellers when details of transactions need to be negotiated.
- Advise clients on market conditions, prices, mortgages, legal requirements and related matters.
- Contact property owners and advertise services in order to solicit property sales listings.
- Visit properties to assess them before showing them to clients.
- Contact utility companies for service hookups to clients' property.
- Solicit and compile listings of available rental properties.
- Rent or lease properties on behalf of clients.
- Present purchase offers to sellers for consideration Generate lists of properties that are compatible with buyers' needs and financial resources.
- Interview clients to determine what kinds of properties they are seeking.
- Prepare documents such as representation contracts, purchase agreements, closing statements, deeds and leases Coordinate property closings, overseeing signing of documents and disbursement of funds.
- Promote sales of properties through advertisements, open houses, and participation in multiple listing services.
- Display residential properties to clients and explain their features.
- Answer clients' questions regarding construction work, financing, maintenance, repairs, and appraisals.
- Inspect condition of premises, and arrange for necessary maintenance or notify owners of maintenance needs.